

Professional Summary _____

I got into computing at the age of 8 thanks to my beloved Amiga 500 system, and later into programming by building custom Ultima Online worlds with an esoteric E-Script language back in 2008.

Since then I've professionally created web pages, command-line tools, React and React Native apps, worked with SQL and noSQL databases, large micro-services applications, automated infrastructure operations with Docker and Kubernetes, converted spaghetti codebases into clean API services and lead a few projects through the software life cycle.

In 2016 I've started learning about about video media and 3d graphics. This allowed me do a few VJ productions and release some open-source projects. This period of exploration convinced me to pivot my career in 2020 towards a game engine that has impressed me the most - Unreal Engine 5.

Creative Skills

Coding Unreal Engine (C++), Unity3D (C#), TouchDesigner (Python), Processing (Java), HLSL/GLSL shaders

Video VDMX, Resolume, Final Cut Pro X

3D Blender, Notch, Houdini **Music** Ableton Live, Fruity Loops

Webdev Skills _____

DevOps Linux, Ansible, AWS, Heroku **Database** PostgreSQL, RabbitMQ, Redis

Backend Ruby, Rails, Elixir, Phoenix, Go, GraphQL

Frontend JavaScript, React
Mobile React Native

Data SQL, DBT, Jupyter, Spark

Education _

• I'm a self-taught engineer. I learn by reading books and building things.

Work Experience

Anshar Studios Katowice

C++ DEVELOPER, UNREAL ENGINE Dec. 2020 -

- Worked on porting (an undisclosed) game from Untiy3D to Unreal Engine 5.
- · Developed gameplay features.
- · Created engine tools for game designers.

Codibly Kraków

Apr. 2020 - Nov. 2022 SENIOR FULL STACK DEVELOPER

- · Worked on a distributed Elixir/OTP application managing thousands of IoT devices in a renewable energy industry.
- Mentored colleagues new to functional programming and Elixir/OTP.
- Contributed to the backend application providing GraphQL API.
- Contributed to the frontend application written in Elm language.

Software Mansion Kraków

Nov. 2019 - Apr. 2020 SENIOR FULL STACK DEVELOPER

- · Worked on a React Native application. Refactored old web JavaScript code, introduced a framework for sharing JavaScript between platforms.
- Developed a hardware-accelerated video encoding module for Membrane (media streaming framework) using Elixir and C++.

Contractbook Remote

SENIOR FULL STACK DEVELOPER

- Oct. 2018 Jul. 2019 • Delivered features in a large Elixir / Phoenix and JavaScript / React application.
- · Designed, implemented and maintained a data processing pipeline used for processing user interaction and financial data. Built reports in Metabase.
- · Cooperated in a multinational remote-first company.

Social Drug Policy Initiative NGO

Kraków

LEAD DEVELOPER Apr. 2018 - Aug. 2018

- · Worked with the product owner and designers to translate the product vision into a product spec.
- Maintained ticket boards and specification documents.
- Set up server infrastructure and build system.
- · Lead sprint meetings and managed the team of 3 junior developers working on a React Native mobile app and on Ruby backend service. The apps are available under https://testdrugs.info.

Relay That Remote

FULL STACK DEVELOPER Nov. 2016 - Mar. 2018

- · Worked with USA-based product owner on giving the product a new direction. Scoped projects, maintained task lists.
- Refactored a legacy Ruby on Rails codebase into a modern API service.
- Built a new frontend application in JavaScript and React.
- Built a JavaScript graphic composition library using modern CSS features.

Base CRM Kraków

Nov. 2012 - Oct. 2016 SOFTWARE ENGINEER

- Delivered features in a complex architecture composed with dozens of Ruby microservices, large SQL and ElasticSearch databases, and RabbiMQ event queue.
- · Worked closely with US-based finance and sales teams, gathered their requirements, wrote specifications, lead and coded the projects.
- Maintained a complex SASS pricing service, migrated to new pricing options.
- Built a system for collecting and processing financial data in Ruby, then migrated it to Apache Spark.
- · Built an internal application for inspecting user data and running administrative actions.
- Lead a company-wide localization effort on multiple platforms.

Social Bicycles Kraków

MID DEVELOPER Nov. 2011 - Oct. 2012

- Developed an application for processing GSM communication between bikes and a server using ProtoBuf, Ruby, and RabbitMQ.
- Built an user-facing web application using Ruby on Rails and Backbone.js.

Left Brain Kraków

JUNIOR DEVELOPER Nov. 2010 - Oct. 2011

• Developed web applications using Ruby on Rails and MySQL.

Freelance Remote

Nov. 2008 - Oct. 2010

WEB DEVELOPER

Built websites using PHP Content Management Systems.